Monday Fezigha ITIL, MCP, BCP

Lagos Island, Lagos, Nigeria



fezigha@hotmail.com



+234(0)07061925668



linkedin.com/in/mondayfezigha

Summary

IT Professional with 13+ years Experience with both business skills and technical IT knowledge, DevOps,IT Operations Manager, IT Helpdesk Manager, Business Applications Manager, technical and desktop IT support in an enterprise environment. Self-motivated and enthusiastic worker with vast experience in many different fields. Bringing forth a proven track record of achievement and a reputation for positive collaboration. Confident, hard working, and committed to seeing results in whatever position I am in. Reliable and dedicated to finding a place that will benefit from my superior skill set and energetic drive.

Experience



DevOps Engineer

Freelance

Jul 2022 - Present (3 months +)

- Provide support for continues rollout of new versions of the components of managed online endpoint
- · Author new alerts to proactively catch any production issues
- Implement, maintain and monitor CI/CD pipelines
- Engage DRIs as necessary to deal with build issues, managing rollbacks
- Filing/tracking work items in order to drive steady efficiency gains
- Hands-on experience with CI/CD practices and tools Azure DevOps (Team Foundation Server), MS Build



IT Business Applications Manger

Tincan Island Container Terminal

May 2010 - Jul 2022 (12 years 3 months)

- Planned, organized, directed, controlled and evaluated the operations of information systems and business applications company wide
- Develop and implemented policies and procedures for IT systems development and
- Designed, developed, integrated, test and implemented information systems business solutions
- Liaison between other Operational Departments and the IT Department
- Administration of Maritime Business Applications systems
- Administration/Support/Backup/Recovery of Application Servers
- Interfaced with suppliers and service providers

Achievements

Worked as Local Administrator with the Solutions team from Bollore Ports France and developers in Argentina to deliver Ipaki External System (https://ies.bollore.com) in Nigeria – a multi-tenant online invoicing and payment system for Bollore group # Worked with local developers to deploy web applications to Azure using DevOps



Information Technology Operations Manager

Tincan Island Container Terminal

May 2020 - May 2021 (1 year 1 month)

- Managed physical and virtual infrastructure of the organisation On-prem and in colocated data centre
- Managed Information systems quality assurance and analysis
- Act as Technical and Administrative Support on Business Solutions, Servers and Services
- Designed and managed server availability and performance dashboard with Centreon
- IT Service and Operations management
- Conduct business and technical studies
- IT Training management

Achievements

Worked as Local IT administrator and B'care Ambassador for ServiceNow, an IT service management solution rollout in all Bollore worldwide (https://bcare.servicenow.com/)

Worked with project team to decommissioning of On-prem servers to co-located Tier III data centre and Cloud infrastructure (Azure)

Led the team tasked with the upgrade of the virtualization infrastructure platform (VMware vCenter)



Information Technology Help Desk Manager

Tincan Island Container Terminal

May 2016 - May 2021 (5 years 1 month)

- Provided technical assistance/support to users on Windows, Email (Lotus Notes) and Maritime Business Applications (OSCAR)
- Managed Backup/Recovery of servers with Symantec Backup Exec and Veeam Backup and Replication tools
- Training and Technical Support on Maritime Systems and Applications
- General Support on network services availability
- Monitored daily performance of the systems and servers
- IT Surveillance administration and support
- Provide support to business systems, network and Internet users in response to identified difficulties

Achievements

Created knowledgebase system for IT and End-user

Initiated use of open-source GLPI ticketing system for incident management



Business Applications Support

Tincan Island Container Terminal

May 2014 - May 2016 (2 years 1 month)



Information Technology Support Specialist

Tincan Island Container Terminal

Education

provident university Delaware United States

Bachelor's degree, Information Technology

2014 - 2018

Bull Formations, paris, France 2013 - 2013

Licenses & Certifications

- Bollore Certified Professional France (BCP) Bull
- Windows Server 2003 Microsoft
- Windows server 2008 Microsoft Microsoft desktop Virtualisation
- ©AXELOS ITIL Foundations AXELOS Global Best Practice
- **IBM support** IBM
- in DevOps Foundations LinkedIn
- in Learning Azure DevOps LinkedIn
- DevOps Foundations: Continuous Delivery/Continuous Integration LinkedIn
- in Introduction to Terraform on Azure LinkedIn
- DevOps Foundations: Site Reliability Engineering LinkedIn
- **DevOps Foundations: Monitoring and Observability** LinkedIn

Skills

Splunk • Jaeger • Zabbix • Terraform • Ansible • Azure DevOps • Microsoft Azure • Hybrid competence • IT Service Management • System Deployment